下一节我们将讨论的是 Docker 映像
The next section we're gonna be talking
about is running Docker Images with
Docker，您会发现，这将更容易一亿倍。
Docker, and you'll see that this
is about 100 million times easier.
首先，我们要了解如何使用 Docker 运行。
So the first thing that we're gonna
learn how to do is use Docker run.
所以 Docker 会为您做一些不同的事情。
So Docker does quite a few
different things for you.
但是老实说，我想象的大多数人都将参加这个课程，
But honestly, for most people that I
imagined will be taking this course,
Docker 运行是您真正关心的部分。
Docker run is the part that
you actually care most about.
我们中的大多数人也许不会用手建造容器
Most of us probably won't be
building containers by hand and
管理所有这些东西
managing all that kind of stuff.
通常，很多时候，警察队伍会处理这个问题。
Typically, a lot of times
the ops teams will handle that.
就像开发商一样
And as like developers,
你对运行容器的兴趣可能比实际建造这些容器更感兴趣。
you might be more interested in running
containers than actually building them.
但谁知道呢 ?
But who knows?
我不是你妈妈你可以为所欲为
I'm not your mom,
you can do whatever you want.
所以我们要这么做
So we're gonna do this.
我们要运行一个 Docker alpine 容器。
We're gonna run a Docker alpine container.
我们已经干过这事了
And we've kinda been
doing this already and
我只是有点喜欢说别在窗帘后面偷看
I've just been kind of like saying
don't peek behind the curtain yet.
现在我们要躲在窗帘后面
Now we're gonna peek behind the curtain.
所以我要回到这里来对比密码
So I'm gonna come back here to vs code.
我在 MacOS
I'm here in MacOS.
我要说 Docker run--interactive--tty。
And I'm gonna say Docker
run--interactive--tty.
我能记起来的跑
Yep, I can can ever remember, run.
然后在那个时候一旦你做了这个
And then at that point,
once you've done this,
你可以做任何你想做的事情
you can run basically anything
that you want to run.
在这件案子里我想说的是
In this particular case,
I want to run let's say,
Alpine ，对，是 Linux 的味道。
Alpine, right, which is a flavor of Linux.
我要说阿尔卑斯
I'm gonna say Alpine.
这就是 Docker Hub 的关闭权限吗 ?
And this is what's coming
off of Docker Hub right?
这就是我们以前所看到的
Which is what we were
looking at previously.
现在我可以说 Docker 会运行 Alpine ，这会隐式运行 :latest ， right?
Now I could say Docker run Alpine, and
this would implicitly run :latest, right?
这将是他们出版的最新版本，对吧 ?
Which would be the latest version
that they've published, right?
现在我建议你不要用最新的
Now I'm going to suggest
that you never use latest.
这只是一把脚枪
It's just kind of a foot gun.
尤其是以后大家都在看这个课程，
And in particular, since people
will be watching this course later,
我将会非常清楚我所使用的版本
I'm gonna be very explicit about
the versions that I'm using,
我要这些演示给你做我写的代码
cuz I want these demos to work for
you with code that I've written.
所以我想说的是 3.10，我认为这是最近的一个。
So I'm gonna say 3.10, which I think
is one of the more recent ones.
如果你之前没有安装或拉动
Now if you haven't installed this or
pulled this previously,
它会花一秒下载所有这些层然后再花一秒
it'll take a second say downloading all
these layers and it'll take a second.
我觉得阿尔派恩最终的形象就像是
I think Alpine,
the final image ends up being like,
20 多兆字节之类的
20 some odd megabytes,
something like that.
这就是高山的意义。
And that's the point of alpine.
Alpine 就像一个很小的 Linux
Alpine is like a tiny Linux,
it has the barebones and
运行 Web Service的必要性，之类的内容，以及其他任何内容。
the necessity for running web services,
stuff like that, and nothing else.
我想我们会再讨论一段时间
And I think we'll get more into that later
there's a whole section just talking
关于阿尔派恩的事
about Alpine.
但是再次，你可以说猫等等，我们可以看到，欢迎阿尔派恩 - Linux
But again, you can say cat, etc, issue,
and we can see, welcome to Alpine Linux
3.10. 我们要求 Alpine 3.10.
3.10, that's expected given
that we asked for Alpine 3.10.
这可能比我们之前做的容易些
Now this probably seems a little bit
easier than what we were doing before
这就像导出和执行控制组以及共享。
which is like exporting and
doing control groups and on shares.
这都是为了你
This just did all of that for you.
所以我们就花了
So we just spent,
我不知道几个小时后就会有一个命令给你
I don't know, couple hours going
over what one command does for you.
我不知道你是怎么想的
I don't know how you feel about that.
但那是真的发生的事
But that's honestly what happened.
这个比较容易做点，比所有人都更容易记住
This is a little bit easier to do,
a little bit easier to remember than all
控制小组和股票之类的东西
the control groups and
the shares and stuff like that.
好了我要退出了
All right, so I'm gonna hit exit.
那就把我们从集装箱里出来
That'll exit us out of the container.
再一次提醒你容器是被制造的
And again, to remind you, containers
are made to be, the entire idea behind
Docker 容器通常是将它们进行旋转和破坏。
Docker containers in general is that
they're made to be spun up and destroyed.
经常这么做
And frequently do that.
比赛使用他们的短暂权利，但他们的时间不太长。
The tournament uses their ephemeral
rights but they do not last very long.
因此，当您处理 Docker 容器时，不需要任何内容，
So nothing like when you
are dealing with Docker containers,
如果不在 Docker 文件中，那么仅假定任何内容都是永久的。
if it is not in the Docker file,
just assume nothing is permanent.
因此，如果您没有运行数据库，那么这是一种好的思维方式。
So that is kind of a good way of thinking
so if you are running a database without
卷并忽略卷，仅为秒。
a volume and ignore volumes for
just a second.
但如果你说如果你用 Docker 来运行所有数据库
But if you say, if you're running
all of your databases with Docker,
一旦您关闭这些 Docker 容器，您的数据就会随它一起使用。
as soon as you close down those Docker
containers, your data goes with it.
所以你得减轻这些东西
So you have to mitigate that kinda stuff.
所以我要给你看一下小路
So I'm gonna show you
just a little shortcut,
因为你的 " 性 " 是一种难以记忆的
because --interactive-tty,
kind of hard to remember it.
你只能说 Docker 会运行对吧
You can just say docker run -it, right?
它所做的就是以交互方式将你放入容器中。
And what this -it does is it puts you
interactively into the container.
所以如果我再次说 " 松油 : 3 . 10 " ，那就是它所做的。
So if I say alpine:3.10 again,
that's what that -it does.
如果我说 Docker 运行 Alpine 3.10
Now if I just say Docker run Alpine 3.10,
说吧好吧
just gonna say, okay, so
它所做的是它的运行 Alpine 是好的，我做到了，然后它结束了吗 ?
what it did is it ran Alpine is like okay,
I did it and then it finished right?
所以这就像不一样
So that's what the -it is like no,
对它没有任何保留我想真正地连接它
no hold on to it I want to
actually connect to it right.
现在我可以说 Docker 运行 Alpine 3.10 和
Now I can say Docker run Alpine 3.10 and
我实际上可以给它一个命令在完成前执行。
I can actually give it a command
to execute first before finishes.
所以，如果我说，它会进入，它会运行，然后它就会结束。
So if I say ls, it's gonna go in, it's
gonna run ls, and then it's gonna finish.
这就是它在容器里的位置
So this is what the ls is of
wherever it is in the container,
好像是根的对吧
which looks like it's the root, right?
这就是最后的部分，而这里的秩序对我们来说是非常关键的。
So that's what that last part is and the
order here actually is very critical for
Docker。
Docker.
因此，您会执行 Docker ，然后执行该命令。
So you do Docker, then you do the command.
那就在这里
Then the next part here.
就像那都是你的旗子对吧
Like that has to be all of your flags,
right,
它，这个 -- RM，所有这些不同的东西。
the -it, the --RM,
all that kind of different stuff.
然后你把这个集装箱的名字
And then you put the name
of the container, and
那么容器名称之后的所有内容都是您要运行的任何内容。
then everything after the name of
the container is whatever you want to run.
如果你不把 LS 放在这里
And again, if you don't put the LS here,
容器里有某种形式的指令对吧
the container has some sort of
command baked into it, right?
所以它会跑来的
And so it'll run that.
除非你让它做点别的
Unless you tell it to do something else.
是 CMD 对吧
It's the CMD, right?
他们就是这么叫的
That's what they call it.
好的。
Okay.
所以，我们可以说， Docker 会运行 Alpine 猫/etc/c事宜，对吧 ?
So just we can say,
Docker run Alpine cat /etc/issue, right?
你会看到这里是 Alpine Linux。
And you'll see here that
this is Alpine Linux.
如果我们把松油 : 3.10 改变为ubuntu:仿生，怎么办 ?
What happens if we change
alpine:3.10 to ubuntu:bionic?
你去吧，有 Ubuntu 18.04，对吧 ?
There you go, it has Ubuntu 18.04, right?
对，这就是我们所期望的。
Right, which is what we would expect.
所以你可以看到我们可以交换任何我们想要的东西只要它在
So you can see here we can swap out
anything that we want as long as it's on
Docker Hub 或在本地构建。
Docker Hub or we built it locally.
所以我要给你一个警告，因为我正在考虑这个问题。
So I'm gonna give you a warning here,
since I'm thinking about it.
很容易在你的电脑上获取很多图像
It's very easy to get a lot of
images on your computer and
Docker 在映像中就像一个三十亿字节的数据，对吧 ?
have Docker take up like a,
three gigabytes just in images, right?
因此，我认为如果您使用 Docker 修剪映像或映像修剪， Docker 映像修剪，
So I think if you do Docker prune images
or images prune, Docker image prune,
Docker 映像修剪，就像这样，这将清除。
Docker image prune, like that,
and that'll clear up.
比如你一直在管理 Docker
Like if you've been running Docker for
a for a while,
这可能给你清理出足够的空间
this will probably clear up
a decent amount of space for you.
但是，下次下载时，您必须重新构建所有内容。
But again, you'll have to rebuild
everything next time that you download it.
好了， Docker 映像上的 Docker 映像仍然存在。
All right, so, still here on
the Docker images with Docker.
我要说 Docker
I'm gonna say Docker.
跑吧我们会说
Run, and we're gonna say -it but
我们要把它放在新的旗子上
we're gonna put it in
this new flag --detach
那就是仿生机器它会运行一些东西
ubuntu:bionic and
this is gonna run something.
它会把它的散列分解为
It's gonna split up the hash which is
the hash of the container of that's
当前正在运行。
currently running.
然后它完成了，但是这个容器现在实际上是在后台运行。
And then it completes but this container's
now actually running in the background.
这就是分离所做的事情
And that's what detach does and
says like hey run this but
我不想在前台我想让它在后台运行
I don't wanna be in the foreground
I want it to run in the background.
所以现在我有一个容器在后台运行。
So now I have a container
running in the background.
所以如果我说 Docker ps，我可以看到这里有两个运行。
So if I say Docker ps, I can see
here I actually have two running.
我的 Alpine 有一个在我之前的例子，对吧 ?
I still had that my Alpine one running
from my previous example, right?
你可以看到它已经运行了 34 分钟。
So you can see this has been running for
34 minutes.
已运行 18 秒。
This has been running for 18 seconds.
现在我可以说， Docker 连接。
Now I can say, Docker attach.
然后我就可以复制并粘贴
And then I can just copy and paste that.
我没有给这个名字，所以我不能附加任何特定的名字。
I didn't give this one a name so
I can't attach to any specific name.
其实你可以给那些不知道的人
Actually, you can give the ones stupefied.
布达我已经知道了我们来吧
Brattain, I already know that is,
let's do it.
所以如果我这样做，这会把我附加到跑步的过程中，对吗 ?
So if I do that, this will actually
attach me to the running process, right?
所以现在，如果我说一个猫 / 等等，你可以看到我现在在 Ubuntu 里面。
So now if I say a cat/ etc/ issue,
you can see now I'm inside of Ubuntu.
如果我退出，它现在已经走了，因为我叫它退出，对吗 ?
If I exit, It's actually gone now
because I told it to exit, right?
但我不想在后台运行这只是浪费
But I don't want this running in
the background cuz this is just wasting
背景下的资源，我怎么杀死它呢 ?
resources in the background,
so how do I kill it?
Docker 终止。
Docker kill.
我猜这张卡上有我的卡片
I guess it kind of showed
my cards on that one.
因此，您可以说 Docker 终止，并且可以为其提供容器标识。
So you can say Docker kill and
you can give it the container ID.
你可以给它短的
You can give it the short one.
你可以给它长长的
You can give it the long one.
长的是这样的。
The long one looks like that.
或者你可以给它名字吧
Or you can give it the name, right?
在这种情况下，我会说 Docker 会杀死我的高山。
So in this case,
I'm gonna say Docker kill my-alpine.
现在，如果我说 Docker PS ，完全是空的。
Now if I say Docker PS, totally empty.
你之前已经见过的这两个东西是我说 Docker 运行的
Two of these things that you have already
seen before is if I say Docker run -it,
你看到我把名字放在这里对吧
you see me put name here, right?
就像我做了我的阿尔派恩，对。
So like I did my -Alpine, right.
原因是我想以后可以参考一下，对吧 ?
The reason why is I wanted to be
able to reference that later, right?
所以如果我说高山:3.10。
So if I say alpine:3.10.
现在如果我回到我的另一个跑来的地方
Now if I go back to my
other running thing here.
如果我说 Docker ps 你可以看到它有我的阿尔卑斯名字
If I say Docker ps you can see here
that it has the name of my-alpine.
这就方便以后参考，对吧 ?
This just makes it easy
later to reference, right?
现在我可以说 Docker 会杀死我的高山
So now I can say Docker kill my-alpine.
现在我的问题是如果我再这样做的话
Now my issue here,
if I tried to do this again,
它会说我做不到那个已经在用的了
it's gonna say I can't do that,
that one's already in use.
为甚么呢 ?
Why is that?
我还可以查看阿尔卑斯的 Docker 日志
Well, I can actually still look
at the Docker logs of my Alpine,
因为我不想把它丢在这儿
it keeps it around because it seems like
I don't wanna throw anything away here.
这显然是垃圾，这不重要，对吧 ?
This is obviously garbage,
it doesn't matter, right?
但如果我有长长的清单
But if I had a long list of things,
它会保留这些原木以防你事后去检查
it keeps those logs around just in
case you wanna check them afterwards.
有一堆自省你可以在那个集装箱的事实之后
And there's a bunch of introspection you
can do after the fact of that container
已完成。
has completed.
显然，这就是垃圾，我不想要。
In this case obviously,
this is garbage, I don't want it.
我要说 Docker 会移除我的阿尔卑斯
So I'm gonna say Docker remove my-alpine.
所以现在它把所有东西都扔掉了
So now, it's thrown everything away
that was using that before and
现在我可以回去再这样做，这次会运行 Docker alpine 。
now I can go back and do that again and
it would run Docker alpine this time.
>> 因此，当您使用刻度时，只需停止该过程。
&gt;&gt; So when you use scale
you just stop the process.
你别装了
You just stop the container.
但这就是你完全移除它的方式
But then this is how
you remove it entirely.
>> 右边。
&gt;&gt; Right.
它会除去所有类似的元数据和
It removes all like the post meta data and
所有这些东西都是为了它而保留的
all that kind of stuff that
it kept around for it.
这很有用，对。
That's frequently useful, right.
这就是为什么在缺省情况下它会这样做。
So that's why it does that by default.
但在这件案子里我正在创作
But in this particular case,
I'm creating and
破坏了容器我想尽快用这个名字
destroying containers and
I wanna reuse that name quickly.
所以如果我把它放在这儿，它会把所有东西都移走了，好吗 ?
So if I just put --rm here, it'll remove
everything once it's done, all right?
所以如果我退出，我就会再次出现，现在我可以继续这样做了。
So if I do this exit, and I come out right
again, now I can keep doing that quickly.
所以， rm 是，你会看到我做一帮人，因为我是懒惰的
So that's what --rm is, you'll see
me do a bunch because I'm lazy and
我不想在后面输入 Docker rm ，我忘了所有时间。
I don't wanna type Docker rm
afterwards and I forget all the time.